Hello, my name is Glancy, I am a health
insurance advisor, my hometown is Thrissur,
so this
is a comparison video of health insurance policies that are still relevant today. So if you are
searching for good health insurance,
try to watch the entire video without skipping it.
Before entering the video, I would like to tell you a small detail.
Everyone asks,
which is the
best health insurance policy? Everyone calls and asks from time to time. But in my personal opinion,
we
can never say which is the best health insurance policy because every month
new products are
coming into the market. So, we
can never say which is the best. Moreover, the
best thing is to take a health insurance because if we get sick,
no health insurance will help
us get a good health insurance.
I still
remember something that
my friend said some time ago.  When we talk
about insurance,
we all know that the company has good health insurance, so why is there a need to take another health insurance? If it is
from a health insurance company, most of them will give the maximum, which is a
coverage of five lakhs. All the companies can
provide the maximum. But when we were like this, our friend's friend was diagnosed with
leukemia
and the treatment
expenses were more than we thought, we
realized that if we had a health
insurance, then as I
said,
diseases never come to us
without asking, no one knows
when or what kind of disease will come.
Therefore, try to
take a health insurance with good coverage. Rather than
doing excessive comparison, take a policy and let's do a comparison. Let's
study it for a year or two and
try to do a comparison. That would be the
best. So let's
go to the video [music] Today, we have
taken four companies for comparison.  The
products are one of them, Care Health,
Care Health, Nibabuppa, Aditya, ICC
Lombard.
Today we have taken the health insurance products of four companies for comparison. In
this, if it is Care Health, then a
plan called Supreme, if it is Nibabuppa, then
a plan called Aspire, if it is
Aditya Pillai, then
a plan called Active One Max, IC
Lob is a new product called Elevate.
Today we have taken four products for comparison. If we
talk about the age limit, if it is in
Care Health, we can join from the age of 18. There
is no age limit. We can take
this policy at any age.
Similarly, if it is in Nibabuppa, once
we join at the age of 18, we can continue till the
age of 65. Even if it is the
first time, we can join at the age of 18. There is no age
limit. In ICC
Lombard too, we can join at the age of 18.
Especially an age limit.  There is no
limit in this. In Nibopa and
ICC Lombard,
we can continue with a float until the age of 30 as a child.
Similarly, if we
are talking about a sum insured case, I will not
mention it specifically because we start with a sum insured of five lakhs for
everything. We can take as many sum insured as we want. The
premium will
naturally increase as we take the sum insured. So, it does not
matter much. We can
take as many sum insured as we want.
Similarly, in the case of room rent,
we can choose any room in all four. There are no
restrictions on room rent.
And in ICC, even if it is a single
private room, we have
an option called room modifier. So, even if
we have riders in all four, we
have an option to choose any room.
Why is it a feature of saying "any room"?
Sometimes when we go to the hospital and get
Sometimes it is not said that a room or a telex room is chosen, but in
some cases, if
a situation arises where normal rooms are not available, if we have to change to a
suite room
or even a deluxe room, it will be
very
useful for us if we choose policies with the option of an extra room. That is why
health insurance
tells us to take policies with an extra room.
Similarly, there is
a feature called restoration or refill. In every
company,
unlimited restoration is provided to us in all four. By
restoration,
imagine that we are taking a policy of 10 lakhs. So even after
10 lakhs, we can use it again in the same
year for the same illness and different expenses.
Now this feature is available in all insurance products.
It is a
new and good
policy that has just been launched. The restoration
feature or refill is
said like that.  All these are known by their names. In
the four, we have unlimited
restoration available. Similarly, the
cumulative bonus is a little
different in the
case of cumulative bonus. If we
look at the Supreme of Care Health, we have a
maximum of 100% inbuilt
in it. It will be added to the yearly and yearly 50%,
that is, if
I took a policy of 10 lakhs, after
two years
it becomes 20 lakhs.
But in this, there
is a rider that says cumulative bonus super, bonus super, so
after we add it, we
get a five-fold coverage. So if a person has
taken a 10 lakhs,
after five years, the cumulative bonus
restoration becomes 70 lakhs. If it is in
Care Health,
then
we have to add a rider called five-fold separately. If
it comes to Nivup, if we
look at Espare, what we have
taken  Since Titanium is
Titanium, if you are up to
35 years of age,
10x coverage is given.
Then, according to each slab,
5x is set in it.
So, if you
go to Aspire in Nivopa, it is a
little better. Nivopa's expiration is what
I always suggest and take for the
younger people. I suggest Nivopa's expiration for those
below 35 years of age.
So, if you have taken
a coverage of 10 lakhs,
we can
take one CR up to one crore.
This is an inbuilt feature in
Anivopa's Aspire. If it is the first one, then as
seen in Kerala,
5x coverage is an inbuilt feature, that is, it is respect
of claim. If there is no claim, it is the same in Kerala too. If there is no claim,
our accumulative bonds will be
added to us in Aditya Vilas.
It is the same 5x coverage. Now, if you
have taken a coverage of 10 lakhs, as
mentioned earlier, it is also in this.  We have
an inbuilt feature up to 50 lakhs, in which we are
given 5x coverage. If we
come to ICC Ombard, there is a variety of
features. What
we can see here is that we can
increase the gear by 20% and
take it up to a maximum of 100%.
This is an inbuilt feature.
But in this,
they have brought a rider called Power Boost.
It is very
attractive. This
is a feature that is not found anywhere in the market. This is Infinity. If
we
have taken a
policy of 10 lakhs, we can go for 20,
30, 40, 50, etc. every year and
go for 100% every year.
So it is a very varied
feature.
This is a power booster that comes in the elevator in ICC.
So it is a variety of
riders. In the
same way, the second next feature is
Pre-N-Post.  In
terms of hospitalization, the
insurance company covers the expenses before hospital admission and the expenses after discharge. If you
come to Kerala, you can claim 60-150 days of
bills, that is,
60 days of bills before hospital admission and
150 days of bills after discharge. If you
come now, similarly, 60 and 150 are in the
first pillar and 60 and 180 are in the
ICC. If you come to ICC, 90 and 180
are pre-post, pre- and post-90,
that is,
90 days before hospital admission and
150 days after discharge,
we can submit bills in this.
Similarly,
a feature that will be considered next is called
day treatment. If you say
day treatment, for
some diseases,
we need to be admitted to the hospital for 24 hours.  There is no
need for a cataract
surgery or robotic surgery.
Due to technological advancements, we don't need to be admitted to a hospital 24 hours a day.
So, such
treatments are covered. Let's call it
day care in insurance. So, all
these are covered by the
day care procedures of these four insurance companies, as well as
ambulance charges. In these four, the
maximum sum assured can be used.
How much
amount is up to us?
Then
another feature that can be considered
is health checkup.
In four of them, they provide us with health checkup.
They say a list.
So, the
health checkup in that list is what we can
do. We
provide most of it cashless.
We book through the app and
go to the nearest labs to get our health
checkup done. Similarly,
consumables  That is, non-medical items, such as
cotton swabs and syringes, are
non-consumable items. In all
four of these, we
get them as riders.
Now, if you come to Kerala, there
is a rider called Claim Shield. Similarly, if you come to Nipah, if you come to
Espee, even if it says
Safe Guard Plus, even if it says
Safe Guard,
there is a rider. Try to choose Safe Guard Plus.
They give it inbuilt in the first pill. If you are in
ICC, it
says Claim Protector.
So after adding the riders,
we get that too.
Similarly, the next
factor to consider is
maternity coverage. If you
come to Kerala, there is no maternity coverage,
but if you come to Nipopi, if you come to Espee,
maternity coverage is given. If
I am asking for maternity coverage, if there is none, then
Nipopa's Espee or Star.
Health is provided by Women Care or Ester.
One of the special features of this is that if
we
look at Espare after nine months, we get
maternity expenses covered after nine months. It
says Miracle Benefit in it. But one thing to
note is that if we take 10 lakhs, we only
get 12,000 rupees as delivery expenses in the first year. But what is the beauty of this?
We get the expenses for the newborn baby covered up to the next renewal time.
So if we
take 20 lakhs, we get up to
20,000 in the first year. If we
take the maternity premium for three years together,
we can get up to 60,000.
So the
delivery expense
rate is low in this starting out, but it increases gradually. That is, if we
take 10 lakhs, it
is 12,000, but  It is like this, second year 24 36
48, gradually, gradually, and
10x coverage is available in this plan.
So if you take it before marriage, it will be
a little more benefit. This
plan called Nivopa's Expert. Then, as I said earlier, the
biggest beauty of baby coverage is that
I looked at it and we will get baby coverage up to sum Ichiri. In
these
four, we do not get this baby coverage up to sum Ichiri. The
reason is that
now, as I
said,
many children have congenital diseases and heart issues right when they are born. Many children have
many issues right when they are born and when they become first babies.
So if this is the case, now if it
is in the department's Aspire,
we will get all this covered. Similarly, if you
come to Adityapur, the delivery expense is
not covered. If you come to the elevator in ICC, it is
covered. In this, there is a
waiting period of two years.
After taking 10% of 10 lakhs, we will get a  We can use it up to one lakh, if we
want, we
can reduce it to one year. Then in this, baby
coverage is called twice, which means
twice the maternity coverage.
We can use it in baby coverage.
Similarly, the premium in this is one, the
rate in this is a little
more comparatively. We are
talking about its premium in detail,
but when we look at it, when we
add maternity premium, there is a big
difference in the premium.
Similarly, in these four products, we
can see a lot of riders. So, if it is the line of care health, we have a
lot of
riders available, about ten riders.
What are these riders? All these are optional
covers. So, when we add this optional,
we get covered, whether it is weight
breed or what we are
talking about is a room feature. When we
add all these riders, it
becomes a beautiful product.  If we
go to this optional cover of Care Health,
we can see a lot of things like Air
Ambulance Wellness Benefit, Kumme
Bonus Super, B Fit Benefit, Annual
Health Checkup, Instant Cover, Claim Shield,
Care OPD, PD
Modification, etc. We can see
a lot of riders. The
main ones
are a few riders that I will mention.
One is Cumulate Bonus Super. As
we said earlier, if we want to
get that feature of getting a five-ext coverage,
we can get it only by adding this optional cover.
Similarly, after
setting what instant cover is, now for those who have ABC, CD, asthma, BP,
sugar, cholesterol, etc.,
after adding this rider, we will get the treatment related to this after 30 days.
Similarly, even though the claim shield is in the claim shield, as
we talked about earlier,
non-medical
Items like this cotton swab syringe can be
done in this, so try to add
these four or three riders that come as the main ones, and if you
look at the plan that says "expiry", you
can see many more optional benefits or riders.
I'm not going to mention all of them,
but one of the main
features that should be mentioned is the fast
forward feature. If we consider
its special feature,
we know that for 10 lakhs,
we can get 12000 rupees
as maternity benefit. But
after adding this fast forward, we can also take three years of premium
together.
We can claim up to 36000 as maternity benefit in the first year itself.
So,
that feature is available only to those who are married.
Similarly, future ready, after
explaining what future ready is for.  This
is a feature that allows us to add a future spouse. That is, once we
add this, we know that there is a waiting period for all insurance policies. There will be a
waiting period of two years or three years for pre-assist. So if we
have taken an optional rider that says "future ready", we can get that
waiting period waived. So,
before getting married, I always
suggest Aspire to those who are not yet married.
Aspire is also a plan because this
feature is very unique. What can I say, if a future spouse has
cancer, what can I say? Imagine that the future
spouse has some kind of illness.
So
we have taken this policy. So, in the
future, the
chances of that spouse getting any insurance normally will be very
low. If this pre-assist has come and
gone, or if he has cancer
or cardiac issues,
sometimes it may not be possible to
add it to the policy. But if
we have added a policy that says "future ready",
We will not have any issues when we add a spouse.
We
can add it to our policy. It is an under-disease,
but one of the good riders in this is called
Future ID.
Similarly, as Safe Guard Plus said, this
rider called Safe Guard Plus is to cover non-medical items, such as cotton swabs, syringes, etc. We add this rider called Safe Guard Plus.
Then everyone else should
try to choose according to our choice. Already has already made a
video about this.
Similarly, if we go through
this plan of Aditya Pillai,
we will be able to see a lot of optional covers. If we
look at this, it says Personal Accident,
Critical Illness, Durable Equipment
Cover, Second
Medical Opinion,
Chronic Care, etc.
I will not say everything in this,
but the main
rider that should be mentioned is the rider called Chronic Care. If we
add this, we will get BP.
Sugar, cholesterol, asthma, and so on, which are
covered by those who have angioedema, once we
add this,
we will start getting coverage from day one.
Similarly, we will be
able to see many riders in this,
so try to choose according to our needs.
I
think if we go to ICC Lombard, there are
many riders
coming. We can see some riders that are of a variety that are not found anywhere else. In
ICC, there are about
18 riders in this plan called Elevator,
but I will not mention all of them.
Let's tell you which riders are the main ones. In this, there is a
rider called Infinity Coir, which is
a very unique feature that is not seen anywhere else. That is, we should
try to add it within two years after taking the policy. If we consider it a special
feature, let's say that we are
taking a policy of 10 lakhs now, but
we have a 50 lakhs policy.  If a
treatment
expense of Rs. 10 lakh or more comes,
this will be a trigger. This can be used once. If
we have added a rider called Infinity Care, let it
be a base policy for Rs. 10 lakh, no matter how many claims we have,
how big the sum insured is,
we can use it once.
This is a feature that is not available anywhere else.
Like a super top up, it is
a feature that can be used for us.
And similarly, there
is a second feature called Power Boost.
This cumulative bonus will be
added and added like this. That is,
after taking a policy of Rs. 10 lakh, 20,
30, 40, etc. What can I say? Gradually,
a 100% is added and added.
That too is unlimited and is not available
anywhere. It
comes in the ICC elevator.
Similarly, another
rider that is worth mentioning is the one called Jump Start.
Why Jump Start?  After adding BP,
sugar, cholesterol, as we said in the first paragraph, after
30 days, if you have
added this jump start here too, you will get covered. If you
have BP, sugar, cholesterol, asthma, etc., you can reduce these features, weight, and
period for 30 days and
get covered after 30 days. Similarly, there is a maternity benefit as a rider in this.
We can see many riders. We have
said inflation protect. Then it is worth mentioning that the
room modifier is inbuilt in this. It
is a single-room room, but we
can change it to a room.
Similarly, we can see many personal accident policies,
health, annual health checkup, etc.
Similarly, if
we have
added this, we can
get covered for non-medical items.  As
mentioned earlier, in order to get
non-medical items like cotton swabs and syringes covered,
we need to add a rider called Claim Protect. In fact, the
biggest feature of this product Elevator is the
riders themselves. We have
mentioned them in detail in the brochure.
But these riders are very unique
riders that are not found anywhere else.
One very important part of this is the waiting
period. We
have a waiting period in insurance. Once you take the policy, you do not have to get
covered every day on the same day.
We
are told a particular waiting period. So if you
look at this,
our policy becomes active after 30 days in all four companies,
but there is no
waiting period for any accident cases.
And similarly,
everything is always said about specials. For
some diseases, slow growth,
DC, piles, kidney stones, etc., which are
slowly growing.
We will have a waiting period of four to two years for all illnesses. The
waiting period is 24 months. Similarly, the waiting period for pre-existing illnesses is
very important.
So if we come to Kerala,
we have a four-year pre-existing illness waiting period. If
we have
any current illness, then the
waiting period for that illness is four years.
But one thing is special about this. If we
add the aforementioned insta cover, we will get the ABCD
i.e. asthma, BP, sugar, cholesterol,
etc. after 30 days.
And not only that, there
is a rider as PD modification.
So if we add that, we can reduce the four years to
three, two or one.
So try to choose it according to our needs.
Now, even if we
go to Baba Uppa, we have a
three-year waiting period for
pre-existing illnesses, but in this, we will get
coverage for BP and diabetes from day one. We will get a  If we add a rider DM rider,
we are
given coverage for BP and Diabetic from day one. Similarly, even if
Aditya comes, the
pre-assist waiting period is
three years. But in this, if we add a rider from Chronic Management, BP Diabetic, and Angioplasty, we are also given coverage from day one. Similarly, if we come to ISIS Slopal, if we come to Veter, we have a
pre-system waiting period of three years.
But as we saw in the first pill, if
we ride a ride called
Jump Start, if we ride a
ride called Jump
Start, we get coverage for asthma, BP, cholesterol, Diabetic, and Angioplasty cases after 30 days. A maximum of two diseases are accepted in this. Even if we add Jump Start,
they give a maximum of two diseases.
So, as mentioned, when the riders are added,
this is when
We get less weight and we are
also offered discounts.
In this, if we
come to Kerala Health, we get a 30 percent discount on
active days. It
gives us a
30 percent discount depending on the steps we take. Similarly, if we are in Nivopa, we get a 30 percent discount.
Depending on the steps we take, and if we have chosen a
rider called cash bag, we are initially given a 10% discount. Then, according to that, we are given a total of 5% discount on renewal. If we have added a rider called cash back,
similarly, even in Aditya, we are
given 100% health returns. However, it
is an inbuilt feature.
Depending on the active days we take,
similarly, if we
come to ICC, we have
a special feature here. If we
have a civil score above 750, we are given a 15 percent discount. After looking at the CIBIL score, we are given a 15
percent discount.
Discounts
are given according to distance. Similarly, the
most important
thing to mention about the premium is the premium. If it
comes to premium,
I will take two categories. If it comes to 30 years, I
will take 10 lakhs. If it comes to 35 years, I will take 10 lakhs.
Now, if we
look at Kerala, it comes
to 12120 for 10 lakhs. If we add claim shield and
take it. If we take it in the
case of the elderly, then if we go to
years, if we
add claim shield and take it, it
comes to ₹49000. The premium is
very high for the elderly.
This is a situation in almost all insurances.
Similarly, if we
come to the category, the premium for two people aged 35 and 30 is
17193 for 10 lakhs. In this, we have added two riders. The
main thing to add is
one that says Safe Guard Plus and
Plus, sorry,
one that says Safe Guard Plus.  The rider that we
add is the
premium of the variant called Tatani.
This is a special feature of this.
Maternity coverage is
inbuilt in it. If you are planning for maternity, then if you are a
little more focused on the four companies, it is a
little better. If we
take the case of those who are primed,
we have a premium that
comes close to ₹52540.
But one of the special features of this is that since
it is 10x Titanium, even though it is a
policy of five lakhs, it
can be taken up to 50 lakhs. It
provides 10x. That is why
the rate is naturally a little higher.
And similarly, even if you look at the first one, the
premium comes at 35 30
paise, it comes close to 12119.
No riders have been added,
but if you look at the special feature of this,
5x coverage is also available in
Kerala. As mentioned, 5x coverage
is inbuilt in it. Similarly, if
you look at the premium, it is 65 60 paise.  We have not
added any riders and
there the premium is around ₹49000.
Similarly, if we
come to ISIS Elevator, if we look at
a premium of ₹10 lakhs,
we have
₹14969 in which we have added four rides like Power Booster, Claim
Protector, Infinity Care Room
Modifier. Although
the rate of this society is a little
higher, but when we
look at the features, it is very
low. As mentioned, for 10 lakhs,
₹14969 comes. If we
add maternity coverage to this, this one feature,
maternity, is added. If we add maternity coverage,
maternity feature rider, the
premium
increases tremendously. If we come to the case of parents, ₹
47630 comes out of this. If
we take it without adding any rides, the
premium for parents is in this range.
Surely, you all have an idea.
I think you have got it.
I made a video just to give you a rough idea
because I think
these four policies are the best policies that have come out in the market right now.
I have compared them today.
Of course, when
comparing, try to go through these four
products one by one.
Similarly, if you have any
doubts about the policies,
my WhatsApp number is
given below so you can
send a message to it.
Of course, I will help you.
Thank you, greetings,
dear ones. If you like the videos of Katukumani, you should join me.